Inventory of the Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Collection, 1937 - 1977; bulk 1970-1975
Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Collection1937 - 1977; bulk 1970-1975
- Series 1: Authors Files
  - , History of Women Part II, undated (Box 28)
  - , Bibliographical Essay on Books on Women for Choice magazine, undated (Box 28)
  - , "Future of Marriage is Grim" Fortnight, 1968 (Box 28)
  - , Resocializing College Women, undated (Box 28)
  - , Material from Tobias' trip to Tennessee May 1, 1972, 1972 (Box 28)
  - , Materials from Tobias' trip to Radcliffe College April 17, 18, 1972, 1972 (Box 28)
  - , Materials from Tobias' trip to Phillips Exeter Academy, 1972 (Box 28)
  - Tobias, Sheila and Kusnetz, Ella, Teaching Women's Studies: An Experiment at Stout State, undated (Box 28)
  - Tobias, Sheila and Andersen, Lisa, What Really Happened to Rosie the Riveter: Demobilization and the Female Labor Force, 1945-1947 - An Inquiry into Research Possibilities, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Tomasson, Verna, "Women as Property" New Republic, 1970 (Box 28)
  - Torrey, Jane W., Psychoanalysis: A Feminist Revision, undated (Box 29)
  - Trans Action, Special Issue: The American Woman, 1970 (Box 29)
  - Trecker, Janice, The Suffrage Prisoners, 1972 (Box 29)
  - , Sex, Science and Education, 1972 (Box 29)
  - , Women in U.S. History High School Textbooks, undated (Box 29)
  - Tresemer, David, Fear of Success: Popular but Unproven, undated (Box 29)
  - Tresemer, David and Pleck, Joseph, Sex-role Boundaries and Resistance to Sex-role Change, undated (Box 29)
  - Trey, J. E., Women in the War Economy - World War II, undated (Box 29)
  - Trinity College, Bibliography, undated (Box 29)
  - Tully, Andrew, America is Squandering, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Unbecoming Men,, undated (Box 29)
  - Uger, Rhoda, and Raymond, Beth and Levine, Steve, Who Discriminates Against Women, undated (Box 29)
  - U.S. Department of Labor, Working Wives -- Their Contribution to Family Income, undated (Box 29)
  - Viorst, Judith, What Worries Me Most about Women's Lib, undated (Box 29)
  - Voice Magazine, The High Cost of Living Off Someone Else, undated (Box 29)
  - Village Voice, Misc., undated (Box 29)
  - Waldman, E. and Grover, K., Marital and Family Characteristics of the Labor Force, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Walker, Lee, A Quick Rundown on Feminist Consciousness-raising Groups, undated (Box 29)
  - Wallace, Michelle, Black Sisterhood, undated (Box 29)
  - Wallston, Barbara, The Effects of Maternal Employment on Children, undated (Box 29)
  - Ware, Cellestine, Problems of 19th Century Feminism, undated (Box 29)
  - Weigand, Jonathon, The Single Father, 1973 (Box 29)
  - Weil, Mildred, An Analysis of the Factors influencing Married Women's Actual or Planned Work Participation, undated (Box 29)
  - Weimar Women Bibliography,, undated (Box 29)
  - Weir, Sybil, The Bacchante of American Home: Robert Herrick's Together, undated (Box 29)
  - Weisskoff, Francine Blau, Women in the United States Economy, undated (Box 29)
  - , "Women's Place" in the Labor Market, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Weissman, Hope, Antifeminism and Chaucer's Characterization, 1975 (Box 29)
  - Weisstein, Naomi, Kinder, Kuche, Kirche as Scientific Law: Psychology Constructs the Female, undated (Box 29)
  - , Woman as Nigger: Psychology Today, 1969 (Box 29)
  - Weitheimer, Barbara, Women in Trade Unions, 1974 (Box 30)
  - Weitzman, Lenore and Eifler, Deborah and Hokada, Elizabeth and Ross, Catherine, Sex-role Socialization in Picture Books for Preschool Children, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Weitzman, Lenore J., Legal Regulation of Marriage: Tradition and Change, 1974 (Box 30)
  - , Affirmative Action Plans for Eliminating Self-Discrimination in Academe, 1974 (Box 30)
  - Weitzman, Lenore J. and Dixon, Ruth B., Alimony: A Quest for Justice in Changing Times, undated (Box 30)
  - Weitzman, Lenni, Sex Role Socialization, undated (Box 30)
  - Wells, Lyn, American Women: Their Use and Abuse, undated (Box 30)
  - West, Anne Grant, The Black and White of Women's Liberation, 1971 (Box 30)
  - Westervelt, E., The Threat of the Road Not Taken, 1974 (Box 30)
  - Westervelt, Esther Manning, Major Contributions: A Tide in the Affairs of Women: The Psychological Impact of Feminism on Educated Women, 1973 (Box 30)
  - , High Education: Currents and Cross-currents, 1974 (Box 30)
  - , The Warm Genius of Women, 1974 (Box 30)
  - , Non-sexist Child Rearing, undated (Box 30)
  - , Current Issues in Higher Education: The Education of Women: Current Experiementation and Research, undated (Box 30)
  - Wexler, Jacqueline, Women in Society: The Search for Personhood, 1970 (Box 30)
  - Westoff, Charles F., The Decline of Unplanned Births in the United States, undated (Box 30)
  - Wheeler, Adade, Illinois Women and the Frontier, undated (Box 30)
  - Whistnant, Charleen, Red Clay Reader - assorted articles about, undated (Box 30)
  - White, Martha S., Psychological and Social Barriers to Women in Science, 1970 (Box 30)
  - White, Marni, The American Housewife, undated (Box 30)
  - White, Marny, The Employed Woman in Contemporary American Society, 1971 (Box 30)
  - Whitman, Marina, Before the Joint Economic Committee, 1973 (Box 30)
  - Whyte Jr., William, The Wife Problem, 1952 (Box 30)
  - Wilson, Joan Hoff, Women's Studies and Feminism: Survival in the Seventies, 1973 (Box 30)
  - , Dancing Dogs of the Colonial Period: Women Scientists, 1973 (Box 30)
  - , What Does a Woman Want? (Toward a Theory of Feminist Humanism, undated (Box 30)
  - Winston, Marian P. and Forsher, Trude, Nonsupport of Legitimate Children by Affluent Fathers as a Cause of Poverty and Welfare Dependence, 1971 (Box 30)
  - Wolff, Cindy, Lily Bart and the Beautiful Death, 1973 (Box 30)
  - Wolff, Cynthia Griffin, A Mirror for Men: Stereotypes of Women in Literature, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Wolff, Cynthia Griffin, Thanatos and Eros: Kate Chopin's The Awakening, undated (Box 30)
  - Wolman, C. and Frank, H., The Solo Woman in a Professional Peer Group, undated (Box 31)
  - Wood, Ann Douglas, The Fashionable Diseases: Women's Complaints and their Treatment in 19th Century America, 1973 (Box 31)
  - , Women's Future in Higher Education, 1972 (Box 31)
  - Woolf, Virginia, Miscellany - Articles on Virginia Woolf, 1975 (Box 31)
  - Yaffe, Barbara and Yaffe, Byron, State Protective Legislation: An Anachronism under Title VII, undated (Box 31)
  - Zabolai-Csekme, Eva, The Female Identity (A Theological Inquiry), undated (Box 31)
  - Zelditch Jr., Morris, Role Differentiation in the Nuclear Family: A Comparative Study, 1955 (Box 31)
- Series 2: Subject Files
  - Abortion, 1970-1977 (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
  - Abortion, Connecticut, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1969-1976 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Anti-nepotism, about 1969 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Anti-fascist women, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Assertiveness training (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Bicentennial planning, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Black (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Black women, 1970-1974 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Books/reviews misc., 1968-1975 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Catalyst, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Caucus, art and religious studies, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Caucus, Boston women and social scientists, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Caucus, chemistry, women in cell biology, women in science, 1972-1975 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Caucus, Committe W and Women's Socialist Group, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Caucus, economics and western women, 1972-1974 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Caucus, history, 1970-1975 (Box 32, Folder 19-23)
  - Caucus, modern languages, 1970-1976 (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - Caucus, women's political caucus and women in politics, 1971-1974 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Caucus, political sciences, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Caucus, professional women, 1970-1976 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
  - Caucus, psychology, 1971-1974 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Caucus, psychology, Report of the Task Force on the Status of Women in Psychology, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Caucus, Purdue, State University of New York (SUNY), 1970-1973 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Child support, 1972-1975 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Commissions, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    Indiana Governor's Commission on Status of Women
    Kennedy Commission on the Status of Women
  - Consciousness-raising groups, about 1970 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Continuing education, 1969-1975 (Box 33, Folder 15-19)
  - Contraception and population control, 1973-1976 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Cornell petition, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Counseling, about 1970 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Credit, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 4-5)
  - Criminals, prisoners, and delinquency, 1972-1975 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Criminals, The woman offender, a bibliographical sourcebook, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Day care, child care, 1971-1976 (Box 34, Folder 8-11)
  - Sex discrimination (admissions, recommendations, elementary), 1970-1975 (Box 34, Folder 12-13)
  - Discrimination (1975 supplement to sex-based discrimination), 1975 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Divorce, 1972-1974 (Box 34, Folder 15-16)
  - Economic think tank for women, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Economics, 1973-1976 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - Education, administration and leadership, 1972-1976 (Box 35, Folder 3-8)
  - Education, adult, 1972-1974 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Education, Agnostic structures in academia: past to present, about 1970 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Education, Comment, 1975-1977 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Education, courses in women's studies, 1972-1974 (Box 35, Folder 12-14)
  - Education, 1973, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    Educational leadership: a male domain, 1973
    Hierarchy, power and women in educational policy making, 1975
  - Education, elementary/secondary sex stereotyping, 1972-1975 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Education, Emma Willard task force, about 1972 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Education, financing and fellowships, 1972-1974 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Education, graduate school, PhDs, professionalism, 1970-1975 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Education and the law, 1972-1977 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Education, National Conference of Women in Education (NCWE), 1975 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Education, newsletters, 1970-1975 (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
  - Education, non-sexist child development project, about 1975 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1971-1975 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    Dept. of Education, State of New Jersey, 1975
    Donna Woman Femme, 1975
    Pittsburgh Association for the Advancement of Women, 1971
  - Education, project on the status and education of women 1977 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Education, role of women at Australian National University, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Education, sexism in education, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Education, Where do women stand?, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Education, women in academic careers, 1971-1975 (Box 36, Folder 11-12)
  - Education, women in higher education, 1967-1976 (Box 36, Folder 13-16)
  - Education, women on university faculties, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Education, women on university faculties, affirmative action, 1973-1976 (Box 37, Folder 3-6)
  - Education, women's colleges and coeducation, 1967-1971 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Education, vocational, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Employment, 1970-1976 (Box 37, Folder 9-13)
  - Employment, United States Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1970-1974 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Equal rights amendment, 1965-1977 (Box 38, Folder 1-6)
  - Feminist newsletters, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    The Spokeswoman, 1975
    Paid Dues, 1975
    Majority Report, 1975
  - The Feminist Press, 1972-1976 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Feminist workshops, misc., about 1973 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Frontiero case, 1973 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Grasso, Ella, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 11-12)
  - Groupies, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Health services, Wesleyan/Middletown, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - United States Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, Women's Action Program, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Higher Education Resources for Women (HERS), 1971-1975 (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
  - Women and Hierarchies, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Women's history, 1971-1974 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Homosexuality, 1972-1974 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Household workers, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Human rights, 1970-1975 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Insurance and women, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - International, 1973-1977 (Box 39, Folder 10-11)
  - Know, Inc., 1973 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Labor unions, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Women and the law, 1969-1975 (Box 39, Folder 14-15)
  - Lawyers, women lawyers and lawyers in women's lib, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Lester, Richard, Antibias Regulation of Universities, responses1974-1975 (Box 39, Folder 17-19)
  - Marriage, 1971-1973 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Maternity, 1970-1976 (Box 40, Folder 2-3)
  - Media, 1970-1976 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Motherhood, about 1970 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - New Democratic Coalition (NDC)Women's Issues/Rights Committee, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Notes, Caroline Bird (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Notes, the conference on black women (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Notes, lectures and misc., about 1970 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Notes, history of feminist movement, current research on the history of women (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Notes, history of working women (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Notes, law and women (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Notes, lecture on women and work (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Note, The Movement (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Notes, New England regional meeting (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Notes, sexuality (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Notes, theology, Lewis Swidler (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Notes, welfare rights (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Notes, women and the burden of poverty (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Notes, women's history, spring term, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Notes, women in medicine (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Notes, work (from UAW [United Auto Workers] resolutions (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Notes, workplace (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - NOW (National Organization for Women), 1976-1977 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Politics, Eagleton Center for the American Woman and Politics, 1971-1973 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Poverty, 1973 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - A Matter of Simple Justice: President's Task Force Report on Women's Rights and Responsibilities, 1970 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Press (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Sixteen Reports on the Status of Professional Women, 1970 (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Project Womanhouse, about 1970 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Prostitution, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Rape, 1972-1976 (Box 41, Folder 3-4)
  - Religion, 1970-1976 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Research, sex differences, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Research, Smithsonian research reports, 1971-1973 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Sexism in science, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Theater, 1968-1973 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Welfare rights, 1970-1973 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Women: A Journal of Liberation, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Women in politics, The Speaker's Handbook for the Connecticut Women's Political Caucus, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Women uniting to end the war, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Women's Action Alliance, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Women's Action Program (WAP), 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Women's colleges, Association of American Colleges, A Feminist Approach to the Women's College, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Women's Equity Action League (WEAL), 1967-1973 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Women's liberation position papers (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Women's liberation (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Women's liberation, articles (Box 42, Folder 3-5)
  - Women's liberation, Notes from the Second Year: Women's Liberation: Writings of the Radical Feminists, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Women's liberation classics, 1969-1971 (Box 42, Folder 7-12)
    Newsletters, newspapers, zines, pamphlets, etc.
  - Women's literature (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Women's rights in the professions, 1972 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Women's Rights Law Reporter, 1972 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Women's roles (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Women's Studies, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Women's Studies Newsletter, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Work, labor force participation table (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Working women, 1971-1976 (Box 43, Folder 4-5)
  - Working women, Mary Rowe papers1973 (Box 43, Folder 6)